A Finding Aid to the Ivan C. Karp Papers and OK Harris Works of Art Gallery Records, 1960-2014, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Photographic Materials, 1960s-2014; bulk 1969-1999; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 32 Linear feet Boxes 44-76
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1970s-2002; 7.7; Archival Resource Key
    - Photo Book - OK Harris Offices, Staff and Exhibition Space, 1970s-2000s; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - OK Harris Gallery, Interior Views and Kitchen Space - Slides, 2002; 1982-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Artwork - Negatives, circa 1960s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 3-4)
- Ivan C. Karp Personal Papers, 1961-2012; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 4 Linear feet Boxes 76-79
  The Ivan C. Karp papers consist mainly of journals that record travel and daily life. There are a large number of obituaries from print and internet sources along with other biographical information, published versions of brief interviews with Karp conducted for various purposes, writings, a few materials relating to business and academic activities, and some photographs.
  The majority of this series consists of photocopies of Ivan C. Karp's journals from the period 1950-2012 (bulk 1991-2012). The earliest are travel journals written during trips to Italy, Spain, France, and more unusual destinations such as Bulgaria, Tunisia, Egypt, Poland, and Guatemala. The observant and thoughtul young Ivan Karp included salient details of travel and everyday life. Some entries are accompanied by drawings, and his interest in wordplay is evident. Later daily journals, written when Karp was an established art dealer, are more organized and less personal. Photographs, clippings, maps, and wine labels are occasionally included to illustrate statements or add interest. He wrote about scheduled activities, food and wine, sports, music, politics, and often commented on the weather. While daily journals record travel experiences at home and abroad, little mention is made of family or friends.
  Writings by Karp include articles, introductions and essays for exhibition catalogs, and a chapter in a book about the business of art. Among the writings by others is I Married an Art Dealer by Marilynn Karp. Also found are an academic paper, "Reflections on American Super Realism and Photo Realism" by Michael Jucker, and a dissertation by Suzanne Pines, "Five Photo-Realists: Process and Perceptions" (Columbia University, 1979). Among the small number of photographs are several digitial copies of earlier images of Karp including him in uniform during World War II and several at his gallery.
  - Resumes and Bibliographies, 1976-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Obituaries and Appreciations, 2012; Archival Resource Key; Includes 1 electronic disc (CD) (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Obituaries, Internet, 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Interviews with Ivan C. Karp, undated; 1984-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 8-9)
  - Writings by Ivan C. Karp, 1963-2012; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 10-13)
  - Writings By Others Relating to Ivan C. Karp, 1991-2002; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 14)
  - Book by Marilynn Karp, 2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 15)
  - Academic Paper by Michael Jucker, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 16)
  - Dissertation by Suzanne Pines, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 76, Folder 17)
  - Anonymous Arts Recovery Society File, undated; 1961-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Artist Guest House Records File, undated; 1983-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 2-3)
  - Photographs, circa 1975-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Journals, Travel, Archival Resource Key
    - Holland, England, Ireland; "Parables" Opinions, Observations on Various Subjects (circa 1950-circa 1954), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Sicily, (1933 [not found]); Spain ([1953],1958), France (1958), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Calabria, Sicily, Sardinia, London (1962 July-August), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Brussels, France, Italy, Yugoslavia, Turkey, Greece, Bulgaria, Roumania, Czechoslovakia, Russia, Poland (1964 June-August), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Omaha, Reno (1968 June), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Guatemala, Panama (1976 February), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - France (1977); Prague, Budapest (1978); Spain (1980); Italy (1981); Tunisia (198)]; France (1982), (1977 May-1982 June), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Southern Spain, England, Paris, Las Vegas (1983 February-September), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Sicily (1983 December), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Egypt;Haiti, Palm Beach, Las Vegas, Paris; Italy; Nice, Monaco; Knoxville, Guatemala (1984 December-1984 March)[1987], 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Las Vegas; England, Las Vegas, Salt Lake City, Moscow, Leningrad; Las Vegas, Paris, Israel; Nashville, Southwest, Las Vegas, Santa Barbara, Albuquerque (1987 September-1990 December), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 15)
  - Journals, Daily, Archival Resource Key
    - Volume 1 (1991 February 4-1991 November 7), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Volume 2 (1991 November 8-1992 August 10), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Volume 3 (1992 August 11-1993 April 1), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - Volume 4 (1993 April 1-1994 August 18), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 19-20)
    - Volume 5 (1994 August 19-1995 March 22), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 21-22)
    - Volume 6 (1995 March 23-1995 September 11), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 23-24)
    - Volume 7 (1995 September 12-1996 February 28), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 25)
    - Volume 8 (1996 February 29-1996 July 9), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 26)
    - Volume 9 (1996 July 10-1996 November 3), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 27)
    - Volume 10 (1996 November 4-1997 April 20, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 77, Folder 28)
    - Volume 11 (1997 April 22-1997 August 18), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Volume 12 (1997 August 19-1998 January 21), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Volume 13 (1998 January 22-1998 June 24), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Volume 14 (1998 June 25-1998 October 12), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Volume 15 (1998 October13-1999 April 9), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Volume 16 (1999 April 10-1999 August 9), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Volume 17 (1999 August 10- 1999 December 29), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Volume 18 (1999 December 30-2000 June 13), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Volume 19 (2000 June 14-2000 September 11), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Volume 20 (2000 September 12-2001 May 4), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Volume 21 (2001 May 5-2001 September 28), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Volume 22 (2001 September 29-2002 June 9), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Volume 23 (2002 June 10-2002 September 28), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Volume 24 (2002 October 7-2003 April 30), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - Volume 25 (2003 May 1-2003 August 8), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 15)
    - Volume 26 (2003 August 8-2004 February 3), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 16)
    - Volume 27 (2004 February 4-2004 June 26), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 17)
    - Volume 28 (2004 June 27-2004 November 10), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 18)
    - Volume 29 (2004 November 11-2005 May 22), 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 19)
    - Volume 30 (2005 May 23-2005 August 22), 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 20)
    - Volume 31 (2005 August 23-2006 January 27), 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 21)
    - Volume 32 (2006 January 29-2006 June 23), 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 78, Folder 22)
    - Volume 33 (2006 June 24-2007 January 20), 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Volume 34 (2007 January 21-2007 June 29), 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Volume 35 (2007 June 30-2008 March 11), 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Volume 36 (2008 March 13-2008 July 11), 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Volume 37 (2008 July 12-2009 January 21), 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Volume 38 (2009 January 22-2009 December 30), 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Volume 39 (2010 January -2012 June 13), Archival Resource Key (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Loose Pages (circa 1993-circa 1997), circa 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 79, Folder 8)